thesearchmonitor.com 2019-08-12

# Privacy Policy - The Search Monitor

This website is operated by The Search Monitor, LLC (“we” or “us”). By using and visiting our  
website, completing information forms, and by registering for an account, you agree to the use  
of your personal information as set out in this privacy policy.

### Information Collected: Website Visitors

When you visit our website, we capture the following information:

  1. Personal information including cookies, IP address, and geo-location
  2. Online activities including pages visited and the content or subject matter of those pages.
  3. Behavioral tracking including frequency of visits and time spent on the website.

### Information Collected: Form Completions

If you visit our website and complete a form, then in addition to the above information, we also capture the personal information that you provided on the form which may consist of name, company, email, phone number, preferences, and the topic of information requested.

### Information Collected: Purchases

If you make a purchase from our website, then in addition to the above information, we also capture  
your payment information including credit card details and billing address.

### How do we use the information?

We will use this information in the following ways:

  * To deliver the information requested such as a white paper or guide
  * To respond to inquiries such as a demo requests, job, partnership request, or for account  
support
  * To improve the user experience
  * To process your payment
  * To process account requests
  * To market our services to you

For how we use your information that is collected using cookies and similar technologies please  
see the “Cookies” here.

### Do we share your information with third parties?

We do not share your personal information with third parties, except that our agencies,  
contractors, and technical vendors are provided with access in order to process it for the  
purposes set out in this policy.

We may disclose your personal information if we or any of our assets are the subject of a sale  
or similar corporate transaction.

We may disclose personal information to third parties when we reasonably believe we are  
required by law, and in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding suspected or  
actual unlawful or otherwise prohibited activities, including, but not limited to, fraud.

### How do we use your information for marketing?

We will use your information for marketing purposes such as to send you information  
specifically requested or related to content for which you have shown an interest.

### How long do we keep your information?

We will keep your information for a reasonable period for the purposes set out above.

### Use of Cookies

This website uses cookies to enhance our ability to market to you. We also use data from  
targeting cookies placed on your computer by third parties when you have visited other  
websites. Cookies fall into the following categories:

  1.  **Functionality Cookies.** These are cookies that enable us to provide services to you that  
you have requested such as reports or preferences that you may set after you have  
logged in.
  2.  **Behavioral cookies.** These cookies collect information about how users use a website,  
for instance which pages users go to most often, and if they get error messages from  
web pages.
  3.  **Marketing Cookies.** These cookies collect information about your browsing habits in  
order to tailor advertising to you. These are usually placed by a third party advertising  
network.

If you want to delete any cookies that may already be on your computer or device, please refer  
to the instructions for your file management software to locate the file or directory that stores  
cookies.

### Third Party Websites

Our website links to third party sites which we do not operate or endorse. These websites may  
use cookies and collect your personal information in accordance with their own privacy policies.  
This privacy policy does not apply to third party websites and we are not responsible for third  
party websites.

### How do we protect your information?

We take appropriate measures to ensure that your personal information disclosed to us is kept  
secure, accurate and up to date and kept only for so long as is necessary for the purposes for  
which it is used. We will ensure that any third parties such as our agencies, consultants, or  
service providers, who receive your personal information are required to keep it confidential.

### Under 13 year olds

This web site is not intended or designed to attract children under the age of 13. We do not  
knowingly collect personal information from or about any person under the age of 13. If you  
are under 13 years old and wish to ask a question or use this site in any way which requires you  
to submit your personal information, please get your parent or guardian to do so on your  
behalf.

### Changes to this privacy policy

We reserve the right, at our discretion, to change, modify, add, or remove portions from this  
privacy policy at any time. You are encouraged to review this privacy policy from time to time.
